pinesolutions.co.uk 2016-11-27

# Privacy Policy

PineSolutions understands that you care how information about you is used and shared and we appreciate your trust in us to deal with it sensibly. This privacy policy details PineSolutions’s privacy policy so that you have a full and clear understanding of how and why we use the information you provide. 

By visiting PineSolutions you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Notice. 

**Controllers of Personal Information...**  

Any personal information provided to or gathered by PineSolutions is controlled primarily by our data controllers. For any further information that you are unable to find on this page please contact us at; 

PineSolutions (UK) Limited  
Norfolk Tower  
48-52 Surrey Street  
Norwich  
NR1 3PA   
Telephone: 0333 200 4606 Email: info@pinesolutions.co.uk  

**Customer information that we gather...**  

The information we learn from customers helps us personalise and continually improve your shopping experience at PineSolutions. We use the information to handle orders, deliver products and services, process payments, communicate with you about orders, products, services and promotional offers, update our records and generally maintain your accounts with us, display content such as customer reviews and recommend merchandise that might be of interest to you. We also use this information to improve how our store and platform operates, prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our website and enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf. Find below some examples of this; 

**Information you give us...**  

We receive and store any information you enter on our website or give us in any other way. You can see examples of what we collect below. You can choose not to provide certain information but we may not be able to provide you with our full service. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests, customising future shopping for you, improving our stores, and communicating with you. 

**Automatic Information...**  

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many websites, we use "cookies" and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses PineSolutions. A number of companies offer utilities designed to help you visit websites anonymously. Although we will not be able to provide you with a personalised experience at PineSolutions if we cannot recognise you, we want you to be aware that these tools exist. 

**E-mail Communications...**  

To help us make e-mails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open e-mail from PineSolutions if your computer supports such capabilities. We also compare our customer list to lists received from other companies in an effort to avoid sending unnecessary messages to our customers. By completing an order, wood sample request form, refer a friend request or catalogue request form with the marketing tick box ticked you are agreeing to receive email marketing messages from PineSolutions. To unsubscribe from our mailing list simply click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of every marketing email and you will be opted out of all email communications apart from transactional emails such as order confirmation emails which we deem necessary in processing your order etc. 

**Information from Other Sources...**  

We might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information. 

**Understanding Cookies...**  

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognise your browser and to provide features such as personalised greetings and storage of items in your Shopping Basket between visits.  
The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-on's settings or visiting the website of its manufacturer. However, because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of PineSolutions's essential features, we recommend that you leave them turned on. For instance, if you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you will not be able to add items to your Shopping Basket, proceed to Checkout, or use any PineSolutions products and services that require you to Sign in.  
If you do leave cookies turned on, be sure to sign off when you finish using a shared computer. 

**Does PineSolutions share the Information it receives?**  

Information about our customers is an important part of our business and we are not in the business of selling it to others. PineSolutions shares customer information only as described below. 

**Third Party Service Providers...**  

We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analysing data, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links (including paid listings and links) and processing credit card payments. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes. Further, they must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Notice and as permitted by the UK's Data Protection Act. 

**Promotional Offers...**  

Sometimes we send offers to selected groups of PineSolutions customers on behalf of other businesses. When we do this, we do not give that business any of your details. 

**Business Transfers...**  

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy stores, subsidiaries or business units. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Notice (unless, of course, the customer consents otherwise). Also, in the unlikely event that PineSolutions or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets. 

**Protection of PineSolutions and Others...**  

We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law; enforce or apply our Conditions of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property or safety of PineSolutions, our users or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. This does not include selling, renting, sharing or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in a way that is contrary to the commitments made in this Privacy Notice. With your consent: other than as set out above, you will receive notice when information about you might go to third parties and you will have an opportunity to choose not to share the information. 

**Is the information about me secure?**  

We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. We reveal only the last four digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of personally identifiable customer information. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you. It is important for you to protect against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when you finish using a shared computer. Click here for more information on how to sign out. 

**What Information Can I Access?**  

PineSolutions gives you access to a broad range of information about your account and your interactions with PineSolutions for the limited purpose of viewing and, in certain cases, updating that information. 

**What Choices Do I Have?**  

You can always choose not to provide information, even though it might be needed to make a purchase or to take advantage of such PineSolutions features as your Account.   
You can add or update certain information on pages. When you update information, we may keep a copy of the previous version for our records. If you do not want to receive e-mails from us, simply click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of every marketing email and you will be opted out of all email communications.   
The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. You can also disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-on's settings or visiting the website of its manufacturer.   
However, because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of PineSolutions's essential features, we recommend that you leave them turned on. For example, if you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you will not be able to add items to your Shopping Basket, proceed to Checkout, or use any PineSolutions products and services that require you to Sign in.   

**Notices and Revisions...**  

If you have any concern about privacy at PineSolutions, please e-mail us a thorough description and we will try to resolve the issue.   
Our business changes constantly and our Privacy Notice and the Conditions of Use will change also. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and conditions, unless you have instructed us not to, but you should check our website frequently to see recent changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Notice applies to all information that we have about you and your account. We stand behind the promises we make and will never materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information collected in the past without the consent of affected customers.   
You provide most of said information when you search, buy, post, participate in a contest or questionnaire or communicate with customer service. For example, you provide information when you: search for a product; place an order through PineSolutions; provide information in Your Account (and you might have more than one if you have used more than one e-mail address when shopping with us) or you communicate with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. If you complete a questionnaire or a contest entry form; provide and rate reviews, we will also save this information. As a result of those actions, you might supply us with such information as: your name; address and phone number; credit card information; people to whom purchases have been shipped (including addresses and phone numbers); content of reviews and e-mails to us.   

**Automated Information...**  

Examples of the information we automatically collect and analyse include;  
The Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet.  
Login; e-mail address; password; computer and connection information such as browser type and version; operating system and platform.  
Purchase history, which we sometimes aggregate with similar information from other customers to create features such as Top Sellers.  
The full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our website which includes date and time. Cookie number  
Products you viewed or searched for; and any phone number used to call our customer service number.  
We may also use browser data such as cookies, Flash cookies, also known as Flash Local Shared Objects, or similar data on certain parts of our website for fraud prevention and other purposes.  
During some visits we may use software tools such as JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.  

**Information from Additional Sources...**  

Examples of information we receive from other sources include: updated delivery and address information from our carriers or other third parties, which we use to correct our records and deliver your next purchase or communication more easily/account information/search results and links, including paid listings such as Sponsored Links from Yahoo and Google. We access credit history information from credit bureaus, which we use to help prevent and detect fraud and to offer certain credit or financial services to some customers. 

**Information You Can Access...**  

Examples of information you can access easily at PineSolutions include:   
Up-to-date information regarding recent orders  
Personally identifiable information which includes name  
E-mail, password  
Communications preferences and address book  
Payment settings, which includes; credit-card information  
E-mail notification settings, which includes; Alerts, Delivery notifications and newsletters  
Recommendations, which includes; recent product-view history, prior-order history and Favourites  
Your Account area, which includes; your product reviews, requests and recommendations, your personal profile  

Please do not hesitate to [contact us with any queries.
